soulcast.com 2006-12-20

# SoulCast - Free Blogs, Personal Blogs, Anonymous Blogging in Privacy, and Meaningful Connections

### SoulCast Privacy Policy Notice

At SoulCast, we respect the privacy of the users of our website and services and are committed to protecting it. We have created this policy to demonstrate our commitment to you and to help you understand it.

Because protecting the privacy of the very young is important to us. Therefore, you must be at least 13 years of age to use this website. 

We do not collect personal information, including email addresses. We do not collect or maintain logs of our users' IP addresses and information regarding our users' use of our website and services.

While SoulCast commits to protecting your privacy and doing everything we can to help you remain anonymous, third party associations may decrease your level of anonymity. For example, if you are associated with a third party ad service such as Google AdSense or other service, or if you voluntarily visit third party ad links on user pages or browse pages on which such ads exist, those third party services may track visits or collect IP addresses beyond the realms of SoulCast policies. SoulCast is not responsible for these third party logs nor does SoulCast endorse any action of this nature. To take extra steps to remain anonymous, you may wish to surf the website using a Proxy Server. _Learn more about surfing using proxies._

In order to offer and provide optimized and personalized services, we use cookies. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to a user's browser from a web server and is eventually stored on a user's computer hard drive. Cookies are not associated with any individual user since each account is anonymous.

Visit your Settings to edit your profile and other information. When you're signed in, SoulCast page headers will include a link to Settings. You can delete your SoulCast account from our website through your Settings. 

If you want to visit a site without leaving any trace of the visit, and not generate a record in the log file, you may wish to visit these options. 

**Anonymizer**

You can surf anonymously with the help of a service called the Anonymizer x (<http://www.anonymizer.com/3.0/index.shtml>). Check their site and just type a URL you want to visit -- the Anonymizer does the job for you, securing you from many potential dangers. When you follow a link on a page viewed via the Anonymizer you get there via the Anonymizer again, so you don't have to type a new URL. You can choose between pay or free service, but free service implies certain limitations such as 30 seconds delay before pages are loaded, and only HTTP (pay service allows FTP and HTTPS). There are a few sites that are inaccessible via the Anonymizer, like some Web-based free email services. 

The Anonymizer is probably one of the most popular tools for anonymous surfing, but definitely not the only one. A good alternative is JANUS (<http://www.rewebber.de/>) located in Germany. Janus is free, fast and can also encrypt the URL. Here is a quotation from their FAQ: 

> "JANUS is able to encrypt URLs (uniform resource locator) in a way that these can be used as reference for a server. If a request with an encrypted URL occurs, JANUS is able to decrypt the URL and forward it to the server, without enabling the user to get knowledge about the server address. All references in the servers response are again encrypted before the response is forwarded to the client." 

**Proxy Servers**

You can also anonymize one's web surfing by using a proxy server. Proxy servers are similar to the Anonymizer in that web pages are retrieved by the proxy server rather than by the person actually surfing. But there are several important distinctions: proxy servers don't help with cookies, hostile applets or code. In most of the cases their main purpose is to conceal your actual geographic location. Most proxy servers restrict access based on the IP address from which a user connects to them. 

**How to find your own proxy server**

You can find a proxy server using just about any search engine and they will usually generate a list of Web pages where ISPs give complete instructions to their users of how they should configure their browsers. Try every proxy address and after 5 or 7 failures you will surely find a proxy server that works for you. 

**Is My Proxy Anonymous?**

Not all proxy servers are truly anonymous. Some proxy servers may allow the system administrator of the site that you visit via a proxy server find out the IP address from which the proxy server is accessed, i.e. your real IP address. You can perform an anonymity check test at <http://www.tamos.com/bin/proxy.cgi>.

If you get the message: "Proxy server is detected", then there is a security hole in your proxy, and information about your real IP address will be listed. If the message is Proxy server is not detected, it should be a secure proxy. 

**Final word on Proxies**

Use proxies only when it's necessary. Surfing via proxy servers tends to slow down a site and is an additional load on the network and the servers. In addition, please use proxies for legal purposes only.

**What if the government insists on obtaining info?**

We do everything to ensure privacy. The only information that we will make available if required by law is what's already public on our website, such as the username and blog content.

SoulCast reserves the right to modify all or some of this Privacy Policy at any time without notice. If we change our Privacy Policy, we will post a notice on our website so our users are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information only in accordance with the Privacy Policy under which the information was collected unless we have received explicit authorization from the appropriate user(s) to do otherwise.

**Questions?**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this website or your dealings with this SoulCast, you can send us a post using the tag: SoulCastPrivacy.
